<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <!--Created with jdAppStreamEdit 7.0-->
  <id>io.github.huderlem.porymap</id>
  <name>Porymap</name>
  <summary>A map editor for the Pokémon generation 3 decompilation projects</summary>
  <developer_name>huderlem</developer_name>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.huderlem.porymap.desktop</launchable>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>Porymap is a cross-platform map editor for the Gen 3 pret decompilation projects. Its primary functions are to allow editing map tiles, collision, events, connections, and properties. Porymap provides additional functionality, such as tileset editing and region map editing.</p>
    <p>Those familiar with traditional Gen 3 binary ROM hacking can think of it as the Advance Map equivalent for the decompilation projects. Porymap supports the same features as Advance Map, so Advance Map users shouldn’t have much difficulty learning how to use Porymap. There are many usability improvements in Porymap. The most notable is undo/redo when painting map tiles.</p>
    <p>Porymap reads and writes files in the decompilation projects. It does not read or write ROM files. Therefore, it is highly recommended to use Git for version control when working with Porymap.</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The Main Window of Porymap</caption>
      <image type="source">https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/raw/5.1.0/docs/_images/porymap-loaded-project.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="5.4.0" date="2024-02-13"/>
    <release version="5.3.0" date="2024-01-16" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/5.3.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>Added</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add zoom sliders to the Tileset Editor.</li>
          <li>Add getMetatileBehaviorName and setMetatileBehaviorName to the API.</li>
          <li>Add metatile_behaviors, num_primary_palettes, and num_secondary_palettes to constants in the API.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changed</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Metatile ID strings are now padded to their current max, not the overall max.</li>
          <li>Non-existent directories are now removed from the Open Recent Project menu.</li>
          <li>Hovering on the layer view in the Tileset Editor now displays the tile ID.</li>
          <li>Labels in the Script dropdown are now sorted alphabetically.</li>
          <li>The name of the Heal Locations table is no longer enforced.</li>
          <li>The API functions ddImage and createImage now support project-relative paths.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixed</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix the metatile selector rectangle jumping when selecting up or left of the origin.</li>
          <li>Fix the event group tabs sometimes showing an event from the wrong group.</li>
          <li>Fix the clear buttons in the Shortcuts Editor not actually removing shortcuts.</li>
          <li>Fix slow speed for the script label autcomplete.</li>
          <li>Fix deleted script labels still appearing in the autocomplete after project reload.</li>
          <li>Fix the map search bar stealing focus on startup.</li>
          <li>Fix border metatiles view not resizing properly.</li>
          <li>Fix Open Recent Project not clearing the API overlay</li>
          <li>Fix API error reporting.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.2.0" date="2024-01-02" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/5.2.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>Added</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add an editor window under Options -&gt; Project Settings... to customize the project-specific settings in porymap.project.cfg and porymap.user.cfg.</li>
          <li>Add an editor window under Options -&gt; Custom Scripts... for Porymap's API scripts.</li>
          <li>Add an Open Recent Project menu</li>
          <li>Add a warning to warp events if they're on an incompatible metatile behavior.</li>
          <li>Add settings for custom images, including the collision graphics, default event icons, and pokémon icons.</li>
          <li>Add settings to override any symbol or macro names Porymap expects to find.</li>
          <li>Add a zoom slider to the Collision tab.</li>
          <li>Add toggleable grids to the Tileset Editor.</li>
          <li>Support for custom metatile ID, collision, and elevation data sizes.</li>
          <li>Support for 8bpp tileset tile images.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changed</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Script dropdowns now include scripts from the current map's scripts file.</li>
          <li>Encounter Rate now defaults to the most commonly used value, rather than 0.</li>
          <li>The Collision tab now allows selection of any valid elevation/collision value.</li>
          <li>The Palette Editor now remembers the Bit Depth setting.</li>
          <li>The min/max levels on the Wild Pokémon tab will now adjust automatically if they invalidate each other.</li>
          <li>If the recent project directory doesn't exist Porymap will open an empty project instead of failing with a misleading error message.</li>
          <li>Settings under Options were relocated either to the Preferences window or Options -&gt; Project Settings.</li>
          <li>Secret Base and Weather Trigger events are automatically disabled if their respective constants files fail to parse, instead of not opening the project.</li>
          <li>If a Pokémon icon fails to load Porymap will attempt to predict its filepath. If this also fails it will appear with a placeholder icon, and won't disappear when edited.</li>
          <li>The bits in metatile attribute masks are now allowed to be non-contiguous.</li>
          <li>Porymap will now attempt to read metatile attribute masks from the project.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixed</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix text boxes in the Palette Editor calculating color incorrectly.</li>
          <li>Fix metatile labels being sorted incorrectly for tileset names with multiple underscores.</li>
          <li>Fix default object sprites retaining dimensions and transparency of the previous sprite.</li>
          <li>Fix connections not being deleted when the map name text box is cleared.</li>
          <li>Fix the map border not updating when a tileset is changed.</li>
          <li>Improve the poor speed of the API functions setMetatileTile and setMetatileTiles.</li>
          <li>Stop the Tileset Editor from scrolling to the initially selected metatile when saving.</li>
          <li>Fix 0x0/NULL appearing more than once in the scripts dropdown.</li>
          <li>Fix the selection outline sticking in single-tile mode on the Prefab tab.</li>
          <li>Fix heal location data being cleared if certain spaces aren't used in the table.</li>
          <li>Fix bad URL color contrast on dark themes.</li>
          <li>Fix some issues when too few/many pokémon are specified for a wild encounter group.</li>
          <li>Fix Porymap reporting errors for macros it doesn't use.</li>
          <li>Fix painting on the Collision tab with the opacity slider at 0 painting metatiles.</li>
          <li>Fix crashes when File-&gt;Reload Project fails.</li>
          <li>Fix overworld sprite facing directions if spritesheet has vertical layout.</li>
          <li>Stop reporting Error: Interrupted for custom scripts during project reopen</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.1.1" date="2023-02-21" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/5.1.1</url>
      <description>
        <p>Added:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add registerToggleAction to the scripting API</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Change encounter tab copy and paste behavior.</li>
          <li>A warning will appear if a custom script fails to load or an action fails to run.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix null characters being unpredictably written to some JSON files.</li>
          <li>Fix tilesets that share part of their name loading incorrectly.</li>
          <li>Fix events being hidden behind connecting maps.</li>
          <li>Metatile labels with values defined outside their tileset are no longer deleted.</li>
          <li>Fix the Tileset Editor retaining edit history after changing tilesets.</li>
          <li>Fix some minor visual issues on the Connections tab.</li>
          <li>Fix bug which caused encounter configurator to crash if slots in fields containing groups were deleted.</li>
          <li>Fix bug which caused encounter configurator to crash if last field was deleted.</li>
          <li>Fix map render when collision view was active while map changed.</li>
          <li>Fix the updated pokefirered region map graphics appearing in grayscale.</li>
          <li>Fix the API function registerAction not correctly handling actions with the same name.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.1.0" date="2023-01-22" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/5.1.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>Added:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add new config options for reorganizing metatile attributes.</li>
          <li>Add setScale to the scripting API.</li>
          <li>Add option to turn off the checkerboard fill for new tilesets.</li>
          <li>Add option to copy wild encounters from another encounters tab.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Double-clicking on a connecting map on the Map or Events tabs will now open that map.</li>
          <li>Hovering on border metatiles with the mouse will now display their information in the bottom bar.</li>
          <li>The last-used directory is now preserved in import/export file dialogs.</li>
          <li>Encounter editing has been slightly modified in favor of a more performant ui.</li>
          <li>Pokémon icons in the encounter editor have their transparency set.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix the Region Map Editor being opened by the Shortcuts Editor.</li>
          <li>Fix New Map settings being preserved when switching projects.</li>
          <li>Fix scripting API callback onMapResized not triggering.</li>
          <li>Fix crash when importing AdvanceMap metatiles while enable_triple_layer_metatiles is enabled.</li>
          <li>Fix File -&gt; Open Project not resolving folder shortcuts.</li>
          <li>Fix bug where "Requires Itemfinder" checkbox is being checked by wrong data.</li>
          <li>Fix the map border not immediately reflecting Tileset Editor changes.</li>
          <li>Fix pasting metatiles in the Tileset Editor not triggering the unsaved changes warning.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.0.0" date="2022-10-30" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/5.0.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="4.5.0" date="2021-12-26" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/4.5.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="4.4.0" date="2020-12-21" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/4.4.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="4.3.1" date="2020-07-17" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/4.3.1</url>
    </release>
    <release version="4.3.0" date="2020-06-27" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/4.3.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="4.2.0" date="2020-06-06" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/4.2.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="4.1.0" date="2020-05-18" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/4.1.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.0" date="2020-04-29" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/4.0.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.1" date="2020-03-04" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/3.0.1</url>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0.0" date="2020-02-13" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/3.0.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2019-10-17" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/2.0.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.2" date="2019-05-16" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/1.2.2</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.1" date="2019-02-16" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/1.2.1</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2019-02-05" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/1.2.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2018-12-27" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/1.1.0</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2018-10-26" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/releases/tag/1.0.0</url>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <url type="homepage">https://huderlem.github.io/porymap/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/huderlem/porymap/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/huderlem/porymap</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
    <category>Qt</category>
  </categories>
  <recommends>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
  </recommends>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Nintendo</keyword>
    <keyword>Pokemon</keyword>
    <keyword>GameBoy</keyword>
    <keyword>GBA</keyword>
    <keyword>Hack</keyword>
    <keyword>Mapeditor</keyword>
  </keywords>
</component>
